{
  "categories": [
    {
      "sports": [
        {
          "question": "Who is the only Great Britain athlete to have won an Olympic medal in any of the three long-distance races for women: 5,000 metres, 10,000 metres and marathon?",
          "answers": [
            "Victor Marshall",
            "Michael Foster",
            "Liz McColgan",
            "Chris Richardson"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": 3
        },
        {
          "question": "Prior to Usain Bolt, who was the last man to win the sprint double of 100 metres and 200 metres?",
          "answers": [
            "Christopher Shaw",
            "Carl Lewis",
            "Ryan Marshall",
            "Henderson Crawford"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": 2
        },
        {
          "question": "In 1980 sixty-two countries boycotted the Moscow Olympics in protest at what action by the Soviet government?",
          "answers": [
            "Internet Censorship",
            "Over-taxing citizens",
            "Invasion of Afghanistan",
            "Rigging the elections"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": 3
        },
        {
          "question": "How many rounds did Mike Tyson take to finish off Frank Bruno in Las Vegas in 1989?",
          "answers": ["Five", "Three", "Seven", "Four"],
          "correctAnswer": 1
        },
        {
          "question": "Who was the youngest English player to score a test century?",
          "answers": [
            "Eli Marshall",
            "David Perry",
            "Jonathan Gutierrez",
            "Denis Compton"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": 4
        },
        {
          "question": "Which city has teams called Wednesday and United?",
          "answers": ["Chicago", "Madison", "Phoenix", "Sheffield"],
          "correctAnswer": 4
        },
        {
          "question": "Who won two FA Cups at the beginning of the last century, winning the two matches by an aggregate score of 10-0?",
          "answers": ["Tucker", "Bury", "Coleman", "Russell"],
          "correctAnswer": 2
        },
        {
          "question": "What name is shared by Birmingham, Coventry and Leicester?",
          "answers": ["City", "Marshall", "Andrews", "Jordan"],
          "correctAnswer": 1
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "movies": [
        {
          "question": "Which person snaps their fingers, and dies in Endgame?",
          "answers": ["Thanos", "Hulk", "Black Widow", "Iron Man"],
          "correctAnswer": 4
        },
        {
          "question": "What is Superman's Kryptonian name?",
          "answers": ["Kal-El", "Kor-El", "Jor-El", "Matt-El"],
          "correctAnswer": 1
        },
        {
          "question": "What does Superman's 'S' really stand for?",
          "answers": ["Hope", "Light", "Destruction", "Sanitation"],
          "correctAnswer": 1
        },
        {
          "question": "In Harry Potter Series, What spell is used to open locked doors?",
          "answers": ["Reparo", "Revelio", "Alohomora", "Incendio"],
          "correctAnswer": 3
        },
        {
          "question": "What charm did Professor McGonagall use to bring the statues and suits of armour to life in Deathly Hallows?",
          "answers": ["Petrificus Totalus", "Piertotum Locomotor", "LOL", "Priori Incantato"],
          "correctAnswer": 2
        },
        {
          "question": "Captain America looks Good with a Beard?",
          "answers": ["No", "Yes", "Maybe", "Definitely"],
          "correctAnswer": 4
        },
        {
          "question": "Does Voldemort have a Nose?",
          "answers": ["No", "Not Sure", "Maybe", "Who Cares"],
          "correctAnswer": 2
        },
        {
          "question": "Who is the largest Red Bird in The Angry Birds Movie?",
          "answers": ["Red", "Chuck", "Terence", "Mighty Eagle"],
          "correctAnswer": 3
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "science": [
        {
          "question": "Can the human stomach dissolve razor blades?",
          "answers": ["No", "Yes", "Maybe", "LOL"],
          "correctAnswer": 2
        },
        {
          "question": "There are more trees on Earth than stars in our galaxy?",
          "answers": ["No", "Yes", "Maybe", "LOL"],
          "correctAnswer": 2
        },
        {
          "question": "Which letter doesn't appear even once on the Periodic Table?",
          "answers": ["Z", "Y", "J", "F"],
          "correctAnswer": 3
        },
        {
          "question": "Which type of mammals can fly?",
          "answers": ["Flying Squirrel", "Pigeons", "Kryptonians", "Bats"],
          "correctAnswer": 4
        },
        {
          "question": "Is it possible to Burp in space?",
          "answers": ["No", "Yes", "Maybe", "LOL"],
          "correctAnswer": 1
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the most common element in the Earth's crust?",
          "answers": ["Hydrogen", "Plastic", "Carbon", "Oxygen"],
          "correctAnswer": 4
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the color of a Lobster's Blood?",
          "answers": ["Transparent", "Red", "Blue", "Black"],
          "correctAnswer": 3
        },
        {
          "question": "Women blink nearly twice as often as men?",
          "answers": ["Maybe", "False", "True", "LOL"],
          "correctAnswer": 3
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "literature": [
        {
          "question": "Who was the author of the famous storybook 'Alice's Adventures in Wonderland'?",
          "answers": ["Rudyard Kipling", "John Keats", "Lewis Carroll", "H G Wells"],
          "correctAnswer": 3
        },
        {
          "question": "Who wrote the famous 1855 poem 'The Charge of the Light Brigade'?",
          "answers": ["Lord Alfred Tennyson", "Christopher Marlowe", "Johannes Gutenberg", "René Descartes"],
          "correctAnswer": 1
        },
        {
          "question": "Who wrote 'Where ignorance is bliss, it is folly to be wise'?",
          "answers": ["Browning", "Marx", "Shakespeare", "Kipling"],
          "correctAnswer": 3
        },
        {
          "question": "Name the book which opens with the line 'All children, except one grew up'?",
          "answers": ["The Railway Children", "YWinnie the Poo", "Jungle book", "Peter Pan"],
          "correctAnswer": 4
        },
        {
          "question": "Which is the first Harry Potter book?",
          "answers": ["HP and the Goblet of Fire", "HP and the Philosopher’s Stone", "HP and the Chamber of Secrets", "HP and the God of small Things"],
          "correctAnswer": 2
        },
        {
          "question": "What was the nationality of Robert Louis Stevenson, writer of 'Treasure Island'?",
          "answers": ["Scottish", "Welsh", "Irish", "French"],
          "correctAnswer": 1
        },
        {
          "question": "'Jane Eyre' was written by which Bronte sister?",
          "answers": ["Anne", "Charlotte", "Emily", "None of the Above"],
          "correctAnswer": 2
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the book 'Lord of the Flies' about?",
          "answers": ["A round trip around the USA", "A swarm of killer flies", "Schoolboys on the desert island", "None of the above"],
          "correctAnswer": 3
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "history": [
        {
          "question": "Which country did Germany invade on the 1st of September 1939?",
          "answers": ["France", "Czechoslovakia", "Poland", "Finland"],
          "correctAnswer": 3
        },
        {
          "question": "What was the first country to give women the vote in 1893?",
          "answers": ["America", "Australia", "Iceland", "New Zealand"],
          "correctAnswer": 4
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the oldest known story in the world?",
          "answers": ["The Epic of Gilgamesh", "The Odyssey", "The Bible", "The Histories"],
          "correctAnswer": 1
        },
        {
          "question": "Which of these was one of the seven ancient wonders of the world?",
          "answers": ["Lighthouse of Alexandria", "Taj Mahal", "Great Wall of China", "Macchu Picchu"],
          "correctAnswer": 1
        },
        {
          "question": "Sliced bread was invented in:",
          "answers": ["Scotland in 1902", "Australia in 1897", "France in 1789", "America in 1928"],
          "correctAnswer": 4
        },
        {
          "question": "In which country was the French Revolution of 1789?",
          "answers": ["Mexico", "France", "Italy", "Germany"],
          "correctAnswer": 2
        },
        {
          "question": "Who was said to be so beautiful that her face launched a thousand ships?",
          "answers": ["Nefertiti", "Cleopatra", "Helen", "Salome"],
          "correctAnswer": 3
        },
        {
          "question": "In 1066 at the Battle of Hastings, King Harold was defeated by:",
          "answers": ["Harald", "William", "Tostig", "Ragnar"],
          "correctAnswer": 2
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "technology": [
        {
          "question": "When did the Apple iPhone first become available?",
          "answers": ["2007", "2006", "2008", "2005"],
          "correctAnswer": 1
        },
        {
          "question": "'OS' computer abbreviation usually means?",
          "answers": ["Order of Significance", "Open Software", "Operating System", "Optical Sensor"],
          "correctAnswer": 3
        },
        {
          "question": "Which is a type of Electrically-Erasable Programmable Read-Only Memory?",
          "answers": ["Flash", "Flange", "Fury", "FRAM"],
          "correctAnswer": 1
        },
        {
          "question": "Who developed Yahoo?",
          "answers": ["Dennis Ritchie & Ken Thompson", "David Filo & Jerry Yang", "Vint Cerf & Robert Kahn", "Steve Case & Jeff Bezos"],
          "correctAnswer": 2
        },
        {
          "question": "The most common format for a home video recorder is VHS. VHS stands for...?",
          "answers": ["Voltage house standard", "Video horizontal standard", "Very high speed", "Video Home System"],
          "correctAnswer": 4
        },
        {
          "question": "When measuring the characteristics of a small-signal amplifier, say for a radio receiver, one might be concerned with its 'Noise...'?",
          "answers": ["Fundamental", "Fall", "Force", "Figure"],
          "correctAnswer": 4
        },
        {
          "question": "The sampling rate, (how many samples per second are stored) for a CD is...?",
          "answers": ["48.4 kHz", "22,050 Hz", "44.1 kHz", "48 kHz"],
          "correctAnswer": 3
        },
        {
          "question": "Who co-founded Hotmail in 1996 and then sold the company to Microsoft?",
          "answers": ["Shawn Fanning", "Ada Byron Lovelace", "Sabeer Bhatia", "Ray Tomlinson"],
          "correctAnswer": 3
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}
